<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:5000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:5000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-29T11:50:27+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:5000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Rasa Chatbot</title><link href="http://localhost:5000/2019/08/28/Rasa-Chatbot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rasa Chatbot" /><published>2019-08-28T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-08-28T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:5000/2019/08/28/Rasa-Chatbot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:5000/2019/08/28/Rasa-Chatbot.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rasa&lt;/a&gt; is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/resources/what-open-source&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; software package with user friendly tools to design, train and build contextual artificial intelligence chatbots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll need to have some experience with &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;; at least how to install it and how to install packages with &lt;strong&gt;pip&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt; users, you’ll need to ensure Microsoft VC++ Compiler is installed. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/user-guide/installation/#windows-prerequisites&quot;&gt;Windows Prerequisites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/getting-started/&quot;&gt;getting started guide&lt;/a&gt; will see you through installation, and even create a sample Rasa project that you can try out right away. I’d recommend going through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/user-guide/rasa-tutorial/&quot;&gt;Rasa Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, and working in a new folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;editing-the-files&quot;&gt;Editing the Files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now comes the tricky part - giving the chatbot a brain and a personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First the brains. The chatbot understands a user’s input by learning the various &lt;em&gt;intents&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;entities&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;strong&gt;nlu.md&lt;/strong&gt; file, which is in the &lt;strong&gt;data&lt;/strong&gt; directory/folder. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/nlu/training-data-format/&quot;&gt;Training Data Format&lt;/a&gt;. You can add as many &lt;em&gt;intents&lt;/em&gt; as you wish - just be careful to make their respective examples distinct so that the chatbot doesn’t get mixed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;stories&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;stories.md&lt;/strong&gt; give the chatbot sample conversation flows, so that it can learn how natural conversations would go. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/core/stories/&quot;&gt;Stories&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/core/slots/&quot;&gt;Slots&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/core/forms/&quot;&gt;Forms&lt;/a&gt; are the chatbots memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;domain&lt;/em&gt; file - &lt;strong&gt;domain.yml&lt;/strong&gt; - is like the body of the chatbot (brains, limbs, mouth and all). It specifies the &lt;em&gt;intents&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;entities&lt;/em&gt; the bot should know; the &lt;em&gt;slots&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;forms&lt;/em&gt; it should store, the &lt;em&gt;actions&lt;/em&gt; it can take and the &lt;em&gt;templates&lt;/em&gt; (things it can say). Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/core/domains/&quot;&gt;Domains&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For twe adjustments to the &lt;strong&gt;endpoints.yml&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;config.yml&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;credentials.yml&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;actions.py&lt;/strong&gt; files, I’d recommend taking some time to go through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rasa.com/docs/rasa/&quot;&gt;Rasa Docs&lt;/a&gt;. They’re really good and well detailed. It’s the best way to find out exactly what’s happening behind the scenes, and how you can mould the chatbot in line with how you envisioned it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; some features &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; at times prove quite challenging to design and implement (custom actions are particularly notorious), but you &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; find plenty of help in online forums. Happy coding 🙂️.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like, you can download a sample chatbot that I’d worked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tim-Abwao/rasa-chatbot&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Abwao</name></author><summary type="html">Rasa is an open source software package with user friendly tools to design, train and build contextual artificial intelligence chatbots.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Demand Forecasting For Perishables</title><link href="http://localhost:5000/2019/08/26/Demand-Forecasting-For-Perishables.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Demand Forecasting For Perishables" /><published>2019-08-26T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:5000/2019/08/26/Demand-Forecasting-For-Perishables</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:5000/2019/08/26/Demand-Forecasting-For-Perishables.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demand_forecasting&quot;&gt;Demand forecasting&lt;/a&gt; is “a field of predictive analytics which tries to understand and predict customer demand” in order to “optimize supply decisions”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has the potential to minimise, and even altogether eliminate the losses that result when perishable items spoil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perishable goods are, by definition, items that have a short shelf-life: things like vegetables, fruits, milk, meat and fish, among others. Some can last a few days, but some last merely a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many grocery stores suffer loss when buyers pick only fresh items, leaving the rest of the ‘stale-looking’ ones to go bad. To curb such losses, some have lowered their stock to avoid leftovers; but this could backfire when customers fail to get what they want, and take their business elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with innovative solutions such as advanced preservative packaging, cold-storage facilities, and the operation of in-house delicatessens to consume the stock, considerable amounts of perishables eventually go bad and have to be discarded. Demand forecasting can take this a step further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of software packages in the market today that utilise Time Series Analysis, Machine Learning and/or Simulation models to predict just the right amount of perishable goods to stock. Some can even factor in past trends and rapidly respond to expected ripples in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish, you can make your own demand forecasting model and try it out. It can be as simple as plotting graphs and performing simple linear regression, or even a really long script of complex computer code. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/c/favorita-grocery-sales-forecasting&quot;&gt;This Kaggle competition&lt;/a&gt; might be a great place to shop for insights.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Abwao</name></author><summary type="html">Demand forecasting is “a field of predictive analytics which tries to understand and predict customer demand” in order to “optimize supply decisions”.</summary></entry></feed>